<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="go[1]"> <hw highlight="yes" hindex="1">go</hw> <sound><wav>go000001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊ</pr> <fl>verb</fl> <in><if>goes</if> <sound><wav>go000005.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊz</pr></in> <in><if>went</if> <sound><wav>go000002.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈwɛnt</pr></in> <in><if>gone</if> <sound><wav>gone0001.wav</wav><wav>go000003.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgɑ:n</pr></in> <in><if>go*ing</if> <sound><wav>go000004.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowɪŋ</pr></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a place <vi>He <it>went</it> to the window and looked out at the yard.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes</it> to the office every morning and comes home in the evening.</vi> <vi>I'm tired. Let's <it>go</it> home.</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> downstairs to the kitchen.</vi> <vi>The train <it>goes</it> from New York to Chicago.</vi> <vi>Halt! <phrase>Who goes there</phrase>? [=who is there?; who is coming this way?]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to travel to and stay in (a place) for a particular amount of time <vi>I <it>went</it> with my family to Rome last year.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going to</it> Iowa for a week.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to move or travel in a particular way or for a particular distance <vi>The car was <it>going</it> too fast.</vi> <vi>How much farther do we have to <it>go</it>?</vi> <vi>She <it>went</it> a long way to see him.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> many miles that day.</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> straight for two blocks, then <it>go</it> right/left at the light.</vi> <vi>The street is blocked, so we'll have to <it>go</it> around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>Their relationship doesn't seem to be <it>going</it> anywhere. [=doesn't seem to be making any progress]</vi> <vi><phrase>Where do we go from here</phrase>? [=what do we do now?]</vi> <vi>We've accomplished a lot, but we still have <phrase>a long way to go</phrase>. [=we have much more to do]</vi> <vi>She has a lot of talent. If she works hard, she should <phrase>go far</phrase>. [=she should be very successful]</vi> <vi>These changes will <phrase>go a long way</phrase> toward solving the dispute.</vi> <vi>Would you <phrase>go so far</phrase> as to call them dishonest? [=would you say that they are dishonest?]</vi> <vi>This time you've <phrase>gone too far</phrase>! [=you've done something that cannot be allowed]</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move to or be at a place (such as an office or school) for work, study, etc. <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> church on Sunday.</vi> <vi>She <it>goes to</it> work from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m.</vi> <vi>Their son is <it>going to</it> college in Florida. [=he is attending a college in Florida]</vi> <vi>He <it>went to</it> prison for his crimes.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to do something that involves moving or traveling to a place <un>often + <it>on</it> <vi>We're <it>going on</it> vacation next week.</vi> <vi>The thieves <it>went on</it> a crime spree.</vi></un> <un>often + <it>-ing verb</it> <vi>The neighbors <it>went running</it> [=the neighbors ran] when they heard the screams.</vi> <vi>I like to <it>go walking/swimming/shopping</it>. [=I like to walk/swim/shop]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>go for <dxn>5 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>c</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to move or travel to a place for a particular purpose <vi>I <it>went</it> to see them last week.</vi> <vi>We <it>went</it> to see a movie last night. = We <it>went</it> to a movie last night.</vi> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> to the wedding? [=do you plan to attend the wedding?]</vi> <vi>I may <it>go</it> to see them next week. = I may <it>go</it> and see them next week. = (<it>US</it>) I may <it>go</it> see them next week.</vi> <snote>In informal spoken English, <phrase>go and</phrase> is used to emphasize a following verb. It usually expresses anger or annoyance. <vi>Now you've <it>gone and</it> ruined it!</vi> <vi>They <it>went and</it> changed it!</vi> <vi><it>Go and</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote> <snote>In U.S. English, <it>go</it> by itself is also sometimes used this way. <vi>Why did you have to <it>go</it> ruin it?!</vi> <vi><it>Go</it> get me a towel!</vi></snote></dt> <sn>d</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to engage in (<it>doing</it> something) <vi>Don't <it>go telling</it> everyone what happened. [=don't tell everyone what happened]</vi> <vi>He <it>went blabbing</it> the news all over the place.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place <vi>It's getting late. I should <it>go</it> now.</vi> <vi>It's time to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I was just <it>going</it> when the phone rang.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave a job, position, etc. <vi>Pack up your desk and <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>She's retiring soon, and it'll be sad for all of us to see her <it>go</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to lie or move along a particular route or in a particular direction <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The road <it>goes</it> from the town to the lake.</vi> <vi>His land <it>goes</it> almost all the way down to the river.</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>Are you <it>going</it> my way? [=are you going in the same direction that I'm going in?]</vi> <vi>The car <it>went</it> the length of the street and then turned around.</vi> <un>often used figuratively <vi>She <it>went</it> the conventional route [=she did the conventional thing] by going straight to college after high school.</vi> <vi>He has always <phrase>gone his own way</phrase>. [=he has always done the things he wants to do instead of the things that most people do]</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to provide a way to get to a place <vi>That door <it>goes</it> to the cellar. [=you can get to the cellar by going through that door]</vi> <vi>Where does this road <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be sent <vi>The message <it>went</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be lost, used, or spent <vi>I don't know where the money <it>goes</it>.</vi> <vi>I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they're <it>gone</it>. = (<it>Brit</it>) I put my keys here a few minutes ago, and now they've <it>gone</it>.</vi> <un>often used with <it>all</it> <vi>The money was <it>all gone</it> by Friday. = <it>All</it> (of) the money was <it>gone</it> by Friday.</vi> <vi>“Is there any ice cream left?” “No, it's <it>all gone</it>.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to die <vi>She <it>went</it> peacefully at about midnight.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The time/day seemed to <it>go</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen in a particular way <vi>The evening <it>went</it> well/badly.</vi> <vi>She worked hard to make the party <it>go</it> according to plan.</vi> <vi><phrase>The way things are going</phrase> [=if things keep happening this way], I may get laid off.</vi> <vi>We lost the game, but <phrase>that's the way it/life goes</phrase>. [=it is a fact that bad or disappointing things will happen sometimes]</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to talk or ask about how you are feeling <vi>“How are things <it>going</it>? = How's everything <it>going</it>? = How's it <it>going</it>?” “Everything's <it>going</it> well/fine/great.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>11</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to be given up, thrown away, etc. <vi>I want to keep these, but that one can <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>These old boxes <phrase>have got to go</phrase>. = These old boxes <phrase>have to go</phrase>. [=we have to get rid of these old boxes]</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be sold <vi>The house <it>went</it> for a good price.</vi> <vi>The cabinets <it>go</it> for about $400.</vi> <vi>The painting will <it>go</it> to the highest bidder</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be willing to pay a certain price for something <vi>I'll <it>go</it> as high as $100, but not over that.</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to fail or become weak because of use, age, etc. <vi>His hearing has started to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>The batteries in the flashlight are <it>going</it> and will have to be changed.</vi></dt> <sn>14</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to break because of force or pressure <vi>The dam/roof is weakening and it could <it>go</it> at any time.</vi></dt> <sn>15</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to start doing something <vi>Everyone's here, so I think we're ready to <it>go</it>. = (<it>US, informal</it>) I think we're <phrase>good to go</phrase>. [=I think we're ready to start]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>get going</tag> at <dxt>get</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>16</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe the result of a contest, election, decision, etc. <vi>The election <it>went</it> in her favor. [=she won the election]</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went</it> against him.</vi></un></dt> <sn>17</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to work in the usual or expected way <vi>I couldn't get the car to <it>go</it>.</vi> <vi>I kept working on the engine until I finally got it <it>going</it>. [=I finally got it to work/run]</vi> <dx>see also <tag>keep going</tag> at <dxt>keep</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>18 a</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt>:to become <un>used to describe a change <vi>The building has <it>gone</it> condo. [=the building has become a condominium]</vi> <vi>British currency <it>went</it> decimal in 1971.</vi></un> <un>used especially to describe a change that is not wanted <vi>The tire <it>went</it> flat.</vi> <vi>The bread has <it>gone</it> stale.</vi> <vi>The company <it>went</it> bankrupt.</vi> <vi>Everything keeps <it>going</it> wrong.</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to change <vi>The leaves here <it>go</it> from green to red in the fall.</vi> <vi>The situation <it>went</it> from bad to worse.</vi></dt> <sn>19</sn> <sgram>linking verb</sgram> <dt><un>used to describe someone's or something's condition <vi>I like to <it>go</it> barefoot in the summer.</vi> <vi>There was nothing to eat, so we had to <it>go</it> hungry.</vi> <vi>My letters have <it>gone</it> unanswered. [=have not been answered]</vi> <vi>Her excellent work has not <it>gone</it> unnoticed/unappreciated. [=someone has noticed/appreciated her excellent work]</vi></un></dt> <sn>20</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to make a particular movement <vi>Can you <it>go</it> like this with your eyebrows? [=can you move your eyebrows like this?]</vi></dt> <sn>21</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt><un>used to talk about a story, song, etc. <vi>I can't remember how the story <it>goes</it>. [=I can't remember what happens in the story]</vi> <vi>The story/rumor/legend <it>goes</it> that he left home poor and came back rich.</vi> <vi>The tune <it>goes</it> like this.</vi></un></dt> <sn>22</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be able to fit in or through a space <vi>Will these clothes <it>go</it> in your suitcase? [=is there enough room for these clothes in your suitcase?]</vi> <vi>The box was too big to <it>go</it> [=<it>fit</it>] through the door.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a usual or proper place or position :<sx>belong</sx> <vi>These books <it>go</it> on the top shelf.</vi> <vi>Where do your keys <it>go</it>?</vi></dt> <sn>23</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <dt>:to have authority :to require you to do what is said or demanded <vi><phrase>What she says goes</phrase>! [=she is the boss; you have to do what she tells you to do]</vi></dt> <sn>24</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to use the toilet <vi>One of the children said he had to <it>go</it>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go to the bathroom</tag> at <dxt>bathroom</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>25</sn> <dt>:to make a sound <wsgram>no obj</wsgram> <vi>The bell <it>went</it> and the class came to an end.</vi> <vi>The music was <it>going</it> full blast. [=the music was being played as loud as possible]</vi> <wsgram>+ obj</wsgram> <vi>The gun <it>went</it> bang.</vi> <vi>The cow <it>went</it> “moo.”</vi></dt> <sn>26</sn> <sgram>+ obj</sgram> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to say (something) <un>used in describing what people said in a conversation <vi>So she <it>goes</it>, “Did you write this?” and I <it>go</it>, “Mind your own business!”</vi></un></dt> <sn>27</sn> <sgram>no obj</sgram> <ssl>of a sports team or player</ssl> <dt>:to have a specified record <vi>The team <it>went</it> 11–2 last season. [=the team won 11 games and lost 2 games last year]</vi> <vi>The shortstop <it>went</it> two for four in yesterday's game. [=the shortstop had two hits in four times at bat in yesterday's game]</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>anything goes</dre> <def><dt>:anything is acceptable :there are no rules for behavior, dress, etc. <vi>She dresses conservatively at work, but on the weekends, <it>anything goes</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>as (someone or something) goes</dre> <def><dt><un>used to compare someone or something with someone or something else of the same kind <vi><it>As lectures go</it>, it was very interesting.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <dt>:to be available <vi>There <it>are</it> no jobs <it>going</it> right now.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>be going to</dre> <def><dt><un>used to talk about what will happen or could happen <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> be cold tomorrow. [=it will be cold tomorrow]</vi> <vi>It<it>'s going to</it> rain: if you don't take an umbrella, you<it>'re going to</it> get soaked.</vi> <vi>I <it>am</it> not <it>going to</it> tolerate [=I won't tolerate] any more bad behavior!</vi> <vi>I <it>was</it> just <it>going to</it> call him. [=I was about to call him]</vi></un> <dx>see also <dxt>gonna</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>come and go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>come</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>easy come, easy go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go about</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go about (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) <vi>I'd like to fix this old radio but I don't know how to <it>go about</it> (doing) it.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>Despite the threat of war, most people are just quietly <phrase>going about their business</phrase>. [=most people are just doing the things that they usually do]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go a bundle on</dre> <dx>see <dxt>bundle</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go after</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (someone)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to follow and try to stop or catch (someone) <vi>When the boy ran out the door, his mother quickly <it>went after</it> him.</vi> <vi>The police <it>went after</it> the escaped criminal.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to find and punish (someone) <vi>The government is <it>going after</it> people who cheat on their taxes.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go after (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something or someone) <vi>If you want the job, you should just <it>go after</it> it.</vi> <vi>She accused her friend of <it>going after</it> her husband.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go against</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not agree with (something) <vi>I won't do anything that <it>goes against</it> my conscience/beliefs/principles.</vi> <vi>values that <it>go against</it> those of society</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to oppose (someone or something) <vi>He was surprised when some of his former supporters <it>went against</it> him.</vi> <vi>He was reluctant to <it>go against</it> his parents' wishes. [=he was reluctant to do something that his parents did not want him to do]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to compete against (a player or team) in a contest or game <vi>The Red Sox will be <it>going against</it> the Yankees in tonight's game.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go against (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not be good for (someone) :to not produce the result that is wanted by (someone) <vi>Everything seemed to be <it>going against</it> her but she didn't give up hope.</vi> <vi>The verdict <it>went against</it> the defendant. [=the verdict was not in favor of the defendant]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ahead</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to do or begin to do something <vi>Instead of waiting for approval, they just <it>went ahead</it> and started working on the project.</vi> :to do something after planning to do it or after getting permission to do it <vi>Despite the bad weather, they decided to <it>go ahead</it> with the party.</vi> <vi>My boss told me to <it>go ahead</it> (with the work).</vi> <vi>“Could I sit here?” “Sure, <it>go</it> (right) <it>ahead</it>.”</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more cake.” “Oh, <it>go ahead</it>. It won't kill you.”</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go-ahead</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to happen or proceed <vi>Despite the weather, the party <it>went ahead</it> as planned.</vi> <vi>After a brief delay, the work is now <it>going ahead</it> again.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before the other person or group that is with you <vi>I'll <it>go</it> (on) <it>ahead</it> and make sure that everything's ready when you arrive.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all out</dre> <def><dt>:to do something with as much effort as possible <vi>When he has a party, he likes to <it>go all out</it>. [=have a big and expensive party]</vi> <vi>Her company always <it>went all out</it> [=did everything possible] to make the customer happy.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>all-out</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go all the way</dre> <dx>see <dxt>way</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go along</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue or proceed <vi>The project is <it>going along</it> smoothly.</vi> <vi>On this job there's a lot to learn—but I'm sure you'll pick it up as you <it>go along</it>.</vi> <vi>He was just making up the story as he <it>went along</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel with someone <vi>They were going to the fair so I asked whether I could <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>I asked whether I could <it>go along with</it> them.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to agree to do or accept what other people want <vi>We tried to convince him to support us but he refused to <it>go along</it>.</vi> <un>usually + <it>with</it> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> us.</vi> <vi>He refused to <it>go along with</it> our plan.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be part of something <un>+ <it>with</it> <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes along with</it> it.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go ape</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ape</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go around</dre> <vr><vl>or chiefly Brit</vl> <va>go round</va></vr> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <slb>always followed by an adverb or preposition</slb> <dt>:to go to different places <vi>She and her friends <it>go around</it> (together) to lots of clubs. = She <it>goes around</it> with her friends to lots of clubs.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place that is nearby <vi>I <it>went round</it> [=<it>went over</it>] <it>to</it> his flat.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used to describe the way a person often dresses or behaves <vi>She <it>goes around</it> (dressed) in a miniskirt.</vi> <vi>You can't <it>go around</it> treating people so rudely.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (a place)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go or pass from one person to another person <vi>There's a rumor <it>going around</it> (the office) that the boss is about to get fired.</vi> <vi>An amusing story is <it>going around</it>.</vi> <vi>There's a nasty cold <it>going around</it>: I hope you don't catch it.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go around</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go around (something or someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be long enough to pass all the way around (something or someone) <vi>This belt isn't long enough to <it>go around</it> (my waist).</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><snote>If people want something and there is <phrase>enough/plenty to go around</phrase>, there is enough for all of the people who want it or need it. <vi>There aren't <it>enough jobs to go around</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>what goes around comes around</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt><un>used to say that if you treat other people badly you will eventually be treated badly by someone else</un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go at</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>They <it>went at</it> each other viciously.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at it</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to fight or argue <vi>Our neighbors were arguing again last night. They <it>went at it</it> for almost an hour.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go at (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to make an effort to do or deal with (something) <vi>They had to <it>go at</it> the problem from many different angles before they finally solved it.</vi> <vi>It was a tough job, and I was impressed by the energetic way he <it>went at</it> it.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go away</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to leave a place or person <vi>She angrily told him to <it>go away</it> and stop bothering her.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for a period of time <vi>They're <it>going away</it> on vacation.</vi> <vi>After graduating from high school, he <it>went away</it> to college.</vi> <vi>a <it>going-away</it> present/party [=a present/party for someone who is leaving to live, study, or travel in a distant place]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stop existing or happening :to end <vi>I just wish there was some way to make the pain <it>go away</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go back</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to return to a place <vi>I forgot my purse and had to <it>go back</it> for it.</vi> <vi>What was it like to <it>go back</it> after so many years?</vi> <vi>After college she <it>went back</it> home.</vi> <vi><it>Go back</it> inside! You'll catch cold.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to begin doing something again <un>+ <it>to</it> <vi>I turned off the alarm and <it>went back to</it> sleep.</vi> <vi>He waved hello, then <it>went</it> right <it>back to</it> work.</vi> <vi>She <it>went back to</it> eating her dinner.</vi></un> <snote>The phrase <phrase>there's no going back</phrase> means that you have done or decided something and cannot change it. <vi>I've already signed the contract, so <it>there's no going back</it> now.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to have existed for a particular amount of time or since a particular period <vi>These ruins <it>go back</it> hundreds of years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>a tradition that <it>goes back</it> [=<it>dates back</it>] <it>to</it> colonial times</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have known each other for a particular amount of time <vi>We <it>go back</it> 30 years.</vi> <vi>He and I <phrase>go back a long way</phrase>. = He and I <phrase>go way back</phrase>. [=he and I have known each other for many years]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to think or talk about something from the past <vi>To fully understand the issues, we have to <it>go back</it> a few years.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>I'd like to <it>go back to</it> your earlier comment. [=I'd like to discuss it further]</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go back on (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not do what is required by (something, such as a promise) <vi>She <it>went back on</it> her promise to help us. [=she failed to keep her promise]</vi> <vi>I would never <it>go back on</it> my word.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go before</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to happen or exist at an earlier time than (someone) <vi>We owe a great debt of gratitude to those who <it>went before</it> us.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go before (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be considered by (someone or something) for an official decision or judgment <vi>The contestants will <it>go before</it> the judges tomorrow.</vi> <vi>The case <it>went before</it> the court.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go beyond</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go beyond (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do more than (something) <vi>She <it>went beyond</it> the call of duty. [=she did more than was required]</vi> <vi>We need to <it>go beyond</it> merely talking about the problem.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go by</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of time</ssl> <dt>:to pass <vi>The morning seemed to <it>go by</it> very quickly/slowly.</vi> <vi>Many years have <it>gone by</it> since the last time I saw her.</vi> <vi>They have many happy memories of days <it>gone by</it>. [=bygone days, days/times in the past]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be guided or directed by (something, such as a rule) <vi>That's a good rule to <it>go by</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion from (something) <vi>She may be guilty but we have very little evidence to <it>go by</it>.</vi> <vi>You can't always <it>go by</it> appearances. [=you can't always judge people or things by the way they look]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by (a name)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be known by (a name) <vi>His name is Edwin but he <it>goes by</it> Ed. [=people call him Ed]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go by</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go by (somewhere)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to go somewhere in order to visit someone <vi>I <it>went by</it> (her house) to see her after school.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go down</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to fall or crash to the ground <vi>The airplane <it>went down</it> when one of its engines caught fire.</vi> <vi>The boxer took a punch and <it>went down</it> hard.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to sink into the water <vi>The ship <it>went down</it> after hitting an iceberg.</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go down</it> soon.</vi> <vi>The quality of his work has been <it>going down</it>.</vi> <vi>She had a fever yesterday, but it <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become less or smaller <vi>It may take a few hours for the swelling to <it>go down</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to become less bright <vi>The lights <it>went down</it> [=the lights were turned down] as the movie started.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to stop being visible in the sky :to set <vi>The sun comes up in the morning and <it>goes down</it> at night.</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to eat or drink something <vi>The medicine <it>went down</it> easily. [=it was easy to swallow the medicine]</vi> <vi>I took a sip but it <it>went down</it> the wrong way. [=I choked on my drink]</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to say how easy or hard it is to accept or agree to something <vi>His suggestion didn't <it>go down</it> [=<it>go over</it>] very well with his boss. [=his boss didn't like his suggestion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:to lose or fail <vi>Last year's champion <it>went down</it> in the first round of the tournament this year.</vi> <vi>The regime finally <it>went down</it> [=<it>fell</it>] in a wave of popular protest.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <ssl>of a computer, system, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The network <it>went down</it> this morning.</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:to be remembered or talked about as an important person, event, etc. <vi>He will <it>go down</it> as one of the greatest leaders this country has ever known.</vi> <vi>His name will <phrase>go down in history</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to be sent to prison <vi>He <it>went down</it> [=went to jail] for six years for the robbery.</vi></dt> <sn>11</sn> <ssl>somewhat informal</ssl> <dt>:to travel to a place (especially one that is nearby or to the south) <vi>I need to <it>go down</it> to the store for milk.</vi> <vi>We <it>went down</it> south to visit relatives.</vi></dt> <sn>12</sn> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to happen <vi>We need to find out what's <it>going down</it>. [=(more commonly) <it>going on</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down on (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>slang</ssl> <dt>:to perform oral sex on (someone)</dt> <sn>14</sn> <phrasev><pva>go down with (an illness)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to begin to have or suffer from (an illness) <vi>He <it>went down with</it> [=<it>caught</it>, <it>came down with</it>] measles.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go easy, go easy on/with</dre> <dx>see <dxt>easy</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go figure</dre> <dx>see <dxt>figure</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go for</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to attack (someone) <vi>My dog <it>went for</it> the intruder.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to try to get (something) <vi><it>go for</it> the prize</vi> <vi>If you want to achieve success, you have to stop hesitating and just <phrase>go for it</phrase>!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to accept or agree to (something, such as a plan or suggestion) <vi>I asked her to lend us some money, but she wouldn't <it>go for</it> it. [=she wouldn't agree to lend us money]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>informal</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to like or be attracted to (someone or something) <vi>When I see how she looks at him, I can tell she really <it>goes for</it> him.</vi> <vi>I don't really <it>go for</it> modern art.</vi> <vi>I <phrase>could go for</phrase> [=I would like] a cup of coffee right now.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relate to or apply to (someone or something) <vi>The rule <it>goes for</it> you, too. [=the rule also applies to you]</vi> <vi>“I'd like ice cream for desert.” “That <it>goes for</it> me too.” [=I'd like ice cream too]</vi> <vi>The economy here has been growing stronger, and <phrase>the same goes for</phrase> [=the same is true for] many other areas.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a price)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be sold for (a particular price) <vi>The painting <it>went for</it> more than a million dollars.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <phrasev><pva>go for (a walk, a drive, etc.)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do an activity (such as walking or driving a car) that usually involves going somewhere <vi>She <it>went for</it> a walk/stroll after dinner.</vi> <vi>On Saturday mornings we like to <it>go for</it> a drive out in the countryside.</vi> <vi>Would anyone like to <it>go for</it> a swim?</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt><snote>If you <phrase>have something going for you</phrase>, you have a talent, skill, etc., that helps you. <vi>She's not as young as some of the other athletes, but experience helps, and she <it>has that going for</it> her. [=she has an advantage because of her experience]</vi> <vi>You should be more confident in yourself. You <phrase>have a lot going for you</phrase>! [=you have many talents, abilities, etc.]</vi></snote></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go great guns</dre> <dx>see <dxt>gun</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go in</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>of the sun or moon</ssl> <dt>:to become hidden by a cloud <vi>The afternoon got cooler after the sun <it>went in</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in for (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to like or be interested in (something) <vi>She doesn't <it>go in for</it> sports.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in on (something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to help pay for (something, such as a present) <vi>Are you going to <it>go in on</it> the gift for her?</vi> <vi>We all <it>went in on</it> the gift together. [=we all gave some money towards buying the gift]</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go in with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to join (someone) in a business, project, etc. <vi>His brother-in-law <it>went in with</it> him on his new business.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go into</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go into (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to start to be in (a different state or condition) <vi>After she lost her job she <it>went into</it> a deep depression. [=she became very depressed]</vi> <vi>The criminal has <phrase>gone into hiding</phrase>. [=the criminal is hiding]</vi> <vi>After losing the election, she <phrase>went into seclusion</phrase>.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go into effect</tag> at <dxt>effect</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to start to move in (a different and usually bad way) <vi>The car <it>went into</it> a skid. [=the car began to skid]</vi> <vi>The plane <it>went into</it> a tailspin.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to start to do (something) as a job or career <vi>He wants to <it>go into</it> the priesthood. [=he wants to become a priest]</vi> <vi>Their daughter is planning to <it>go into</it> medicine. [=to be a doctor; to get a job in the medical field]</vi> <vi>Both his sons have <it>gone into</it> the army. [=joined the army]</vi> <vi>His dream is to <phrase>go into business</phrase> for himself. [=to start his own business]</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to talk about (something) <vi>I'll try to tell the story without <it>going into</it> too many details. = I'll try not to <it>go into</it> too much detail.</vi> :to talk about the details of (something) <vi>Having <it>gone into</it> the causes of the French Revolution, the book then discusses its effects.</vi> <vi>“I've had a long day.” “What happened?” “I'll tell you later. I don't feel like <it>going into</it> it right now.”</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to try to get information about (something) <un>usually used as <it>(be) gone into</it> <vi>A problem like that should really <it>be gone into</it> [=<it>looked into</it>] carefully.</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be used for (something) <vi>Lots of time, energy, and money have <it>gone into</it> (completing) the project.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>mathematics</ssl> <dt><un>used to say how many times a number can be multiplied to produce a larger number <vi>6 <it>goes into</it> 18 three times. [=18 divided by 6 equals 3]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go it alone</dre> <dx>see <dxt>alone</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go off</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a bomb</ssl> <dt>:to explode <vi>The building was evacuated before the bomb <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>of a gun</ssl> <dt>:to shoot <vi>The gun <it>went off</it> accidentally.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of an alarm</ssl> <dt>:to begin to make a sudden loud noise <vi>I woke up when the alarm <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The lights in the building suddenly <it>went off</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to leave a place for a new place <vi>He <it>went off</it> to join the army after graduating from high school.</vi> <vi>She <it>went off</it> to America.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to occur or happen <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> as scheduled. [=the meeting happened when it was scheduled to happen]</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to happen a particular way <vi>The party <it>went off</it> well. [=the party was a success]</vi> <vi>The meeting <it>went off</it> poorly.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to begin shouting at someone in an angry way <un>usually + <it>on</it> <vi>Her boss <it>went off on</it> her because she was late again.</vi></un></dt> <sn>6</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:to stop liking (someone or something) <vi>She used to like him but now she's <it>gone off</it> him completely.</vi> <vi>My boss has <it>gone off</it> the idea, so it's been cancelled.</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <sn>a</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to leave (a spouse, partner, etc.) for someone else <vi>He left his wife and <it>went off with</it> [=<it>ran off with</it>] some young thing.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <phrasev><pva>go off with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to take (something that belongs to someone else) away with you :<sx>steal</sx> <vi>Someone <it>went off with</it> my pencil/wallet.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go on</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to continue: such as</dt> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to continue on a journey <vi>We stopped briefly in Detroit, and then <it>went on</it> to Chicago.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to continue as time passes <vi>Life <it>goes on</it>.</vi> <vi>How much longer will the meeting <it>go on</it>? [=<it>last</it>]</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to continue doing something <vi>She <it>went on</it> working [=she continued to work] after everyone else had stopped.</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to continue talking <vi>He <it>went on</it> (and on) about how unfairly he had been treated. [=he talked about it for a long time]</vi> :to talk too much or too long about something <vi>She's always <it>going on</it> about the importance of a good diet.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to continue to be in the same situation or relationship <vi>We can't <it>go on</it> like this.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to go or travel to a place before another person or group that is with you <vi>You <it>go on</it> (ahead). I'll come later.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to do or say something else after you have finished doing or saying something <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>He accepted the nomination and <it>went on to</it> win the election.</vi> <vi>After I finished reading the first book I immediately <it>went on to</it> the next one.</vi> <vi>He <it>went on to</it> say that further tax increases would be necessary.</vi> <vi>Everyone expected that she would <phrase>go on to greater things</phrase>. [=that she would become very successful]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to happen <vi>What's <it>going on</it>?</vi> <vi>No one knows exactly what <it>went on</it> during their private meeting.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>goings-on</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <ssl>of lights, electricity, etc.</ssl> <dt>:to begin to work or function <vi>The lights <it>went on</it> briefly and then went out again.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to form an opinion or conclusion from something <un>used in the phrase <phrase>to go on</phrase> <vi>There's very little evidence <it>to go on</it>. [=there's very little evidence that can be used to form an opinion]</vi></un></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt><un>used in speech to urge someone to do something <vi><it>Go on</it> (and try it): you might actually like it!</vi> <vi>“I probably shouldn't have any more ice cream.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>! It won't hurt you to have a little more.”</vi></un></dt> <sn>b</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal + old-fashioned</ssl> <dt><un>used in speech to express disbelief <vi>“I used to be a spy.” “Oh, <it>go on</it>.”</vi> <vi>A spy? <phrase>Go on with you</phrase>, then. [=I don't believe you]</vi></un></dt> <sn>8</sn> <phrasev><pva>go on at (someone)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:to criticize (someone) often or repeatedly <vi>Quit <it>going on at</it> me all the time!</vi> <dx>see also <tag>going on</tag> at <dxt>going</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go one better</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to achieve more :to move to a higher or better level <vi>She qualified for the finals, then <it>went one better</it> and took first place.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go (someone or something) one better</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do better or more than (someone or something) :to outdo (someone or something) <vi>The company has <it>gone</it> its competitors <it>one better</it> by offering new customers a special discount.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go out</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to leave your home for an activity <vi>I'm <it>going out</it> for a walk. I'll be back soon.</vi> <vi>We're <it>going out</it> to get some lunch.</vi> <vi>On Saturday nights he <it>goes out</it> drinking with his friends.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to be sent from a person or place <vi>The message <it>went out</it> by e-mail to all members of the staff.</vi> <vi>Word has <it>gone out</it> that snow is expected.</vi> <vi><phrase>Our thoughts and prayers go out to</phrase> all the victims of this tragedy. [=we are thinking of and praying for all the victims of this tragedy]</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to stop being popular or fashionable <vi>That hairstyle <it>went out</it> years ago.</vi> <vi>Short skirts have <phrase>gone out of fashion</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to meet someone for a romantic social activity :to go on a date with someone <vi>They <it>went out</it> a couple of times, but it was never serious.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with someone <vi>I've been <it>going out</it> with her for quite a while now. = We've been <it>going out</it> for quite a while now.</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to stop working <vi>The electricity suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to stop shining or burning <vi>The fire/candle <it>went out</it>.</vi> <vi>All the lights suddenly <it>went out</it>.</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to try to become a member of a team, group, etc. <un>usually + <it>for</it> <vi>He <it>went out for</it> football last year. = He <it>went out for</it> the football team last year.</vi> <vi>She <it>went out</it> [=<it>tried out</it>] <it>for</it> the school play.</vi></un></dt> <sn>7</sn> <ssl>of the tide</ssl> <dt>:to drop to a lower level <vi>The tide is <it>going out</it> [=(more formally) <it>ebbing</it>] now.</vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:to be broadcast on the radio, television, etc. <vi>A distress call <it>went out</it> three hours ago.</vi> <un>often + <it>over</it> <vi>Warnings about the approaching storm <it>went out over</it> the radio.</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go over</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to move or travel to a particular place or person <vi>He <it>went over</it> and stood by the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over</it> and hugged her.</vi> <vi>I think I see Jane. Let's <it>go over</it> and say hello.</vi> <un>often + <it>to</it> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> the window.</vi> <vi>He <it>went over to</it> her and hugged her.</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to change sides in a disagreement, competition, etc. <un>usually + <it>to</it> <vi>After several years of supporting us, he <it>went over to</it> our competitors.</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <dt>:to be accepted or received in a particular way <vi>He tried to make a joke but it <it>went over</it> badly. [=no one thought his joke was funny]</vi> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well.</vi> <un>often + <it>with</it> <vi>Her proposal didn't <it>go over</it> very well <it>with</it> the boss. [=the boss didn't like her proposal]</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <phrasev><pva>go over (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to talk about or think about (something) carefully <vi>He <it>went over</it> all the arguments before making up his mind.</vi> <vi>We <it>went over</it> the accident again and again in our minds.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look at or study (something) again in order to correct it, learn it, etc. <vi>The students were told to <it>go over</it> their essays.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go over</it> the instructions.</vi> <vi>an actress <it>going over</it> her lines</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go the distance</dre> <dx>see <dxt>distance</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>go there</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to start to talk or think about something <un>usually used in negative statements <vi>“Do you remember when we were dating?” “Let's not <it>go there</it>.” = “I don't want to <it>go there</it>.” = “Don't <it>go there</it>.” [=I don't want to talk about that]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go through</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to study or look at (something) in a careful way <vi>The book <it>goes through</it> every detail of the French Revolution.</vi> <vi>Let's <it>go through</it> the plan one more time.</vi></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to look in or at (something) in order to find something :to search in or through (something) <vi>I found him <it>going through</it> my closet.</vi></dt> <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to experience (something) <vi>He's <it>going through</it> a painful divorce.</vi> <vi>I understand what you're <it>going through</it>.</vi> <vi>In order to learn the job well, you have to <it>go through</it> several months of training.</vi> <vi>The book has already <it>gone through</it> four editions. [=the publishers have already released four editions of the book]</vi></dt> <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to spend or use all of (something) <vi>He <it>went through</it> all the money he inherited.</vi> <vi>They <it>went through</it> three bottles of wine with dinner.</vi></dt> <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to occur throughout (something) <vi>A note of despair <it>goes through</it> the narrative. [=there is a note of despair throughout the narrative]</vi> <snote>If something (such as an idea or a song) is <phrase>going through your head/mind</phrase>, you are thinking about it or remembering it. <vi>I don't know what was <it>going through her mind</it> [=I don't know what her thoughts were; I don't know why she did this] when she agreed to help him.</vi> <vi>That song keeps <it>going through my head</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>f</sn> <dt>:to do (something) <vi>It took him about an hour to <it>go through</it> his usual morning routine.</vi> <vi>Before we practice the next section, let's <it>go through</it> the chorus once again.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go through the motions</tag> at <dxt>motion</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><snote>Something (such as a law or contract) that <phrase>goes through</phrase> is officially accepted and approved. <vi>The bill is expected to <it>go through</it> easily.</vi> <vi>The proposed deal failed to <it>go through</it>.</vi> <vi>The bill <phrase>went through Congress/Parliament</phrase> [=was passed by Congress/Parliament] without difficulty and soon became law.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go through with (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to do (something that you have thought or talked about) <vi>He was always threatening to quit his job, but I never thought he'd actually <it>go through with</it> it. [=I never thought he would actually do it]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to begin to be in (a particular state, condition, or situation) <vi>You need to <phrase>go to sleep</phrase>.</vi> <vi>The countries <phrase>went to war</phrase>.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to be given to (someone or something) <vi>First prize <it>went to</it> the team from Chicago.</vi> <vi>The property will <it>go to</it> his wife if he dies before she does.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go to (trouble or expense)</pva></phrasev> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:to do something that causes you (trouble or expense) <vi>You shouldn't <it>go to all this trouble</it> just for me.</vi> <vi>They <it>went to a lot of expense</it> [=they spent a lot of money] to make sure that the job was done correctly.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go together</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <slb>not used in progressive tenses</slb> <dt>:to be suited to or appropriate for each other <vi>The tie and his suit <it>go together</it> well.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>2 (below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>somewhat old-fashioned</ssl> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship <vi>They've been <it>going together</it> for several years.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go with <dxn>(below)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go to show/prove</dre> <def><dt>:to help show or prove something <vi>Her success <phrase>goes to show</phrase> that if you work hard, you can make your dreams come true.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go toward(s)</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go toward(s) (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to help pay for (something) <vi>My extra income is <it>going towards</it> a new car.</vi> <vi>Your donations will <it>go toward</it> better sanitation for refugees.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go under</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to sink below the surface of the water <vi>The ship <it>went under</it> after being struck by a torpedo.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to fail :to not succeed <vi>The company has been losing money and is in danger of <it>going under</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go up</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:to rise to a higher level <vi>Prices are expected to <it>go up</it> soon.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to become brighter <vi>The lights <it>went up</it> [=the lights were turned up] when the movie ended.</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to be built <vi>A new store is <it>going up</it> downtown.</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to travel <it>to</it> a place (especially one that is to the north) <vi>We <it>went up to</it> the lake for the weekend.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go with</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><sn>1</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to have a continuing romantic relationship with (someone) :to date (someone) <vi>I've been <it>going with</it> her for quite a while now.</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go out <dxn>4b (above)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>go together <dxn>2 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (something)</pva></phrasev> <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to be suitable for or appropriate with (something) <vi>The skirt she's wearing doesn't really <it>go with</it> [=<it>match</it>] her blouse.</vi> <vi>The tie <it>goes</it> (well) <it>with</it> his suit.</vi> <vi>Do you think this wine will <it>go</it> well <it>with</it> dinner?</vi> <dx>see also <dxt>go together <dxn>1 (above)</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to exist or occur as a necessary part of (something) <vi>If I want the job I have to accept the stress that <it>goes with</it> it.</vi> <vi>There are a lot of responsibilities that <it>go with</it> starting your own business.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go with the territory</tag> at <dxt>territory</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <phrasev><pva>go with (someone or something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to choose or use (someone or something) <vi>After thinking about who to offer the job to, they decided to <it>go with</it> the more experienced candidate.</vi> <vi>The golfer <it>went with</it> an iron off the tee. [=the golfer used an iron for her tee shot]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>go without</dre> <gram>phrasal verb</gram> <def><phrasev><pva>go without</pva> <pvl>or</pvl> <pva>go without (something)</pva></phrasev> <dt>:to not have (something) :to live or continue without having (something) <vi>How long can you <it>go without</it> sleeping/sleep?</vi> <vi>If you can't afford a new car, you'll just have to <it>go without</it>.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>here goes (nothing)</dre> <dx>see <dxt>here</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>here/there you go (again)</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is happening again or in the same way that it has happened before <vi><it>There you go</it>, making a big deal out of nothing.</vi> <vi>When I saw his name in the headlines I thought, “<it>Here we go again</it>.”</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>how goes it?</dre> <def><dt><un>used as an informal greeting <vi>Hi Paul. <it>How goes it</it>? [=how are you?]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>ready, set, go</dre> <dx>see <dxt>ready</dxt></dx></dro> <dro><dre>there go/goes</dre> <def><sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something is no longer available or possible <vi>Look at that traffic jam! <it>There goes</it> our only chance of arriving on time. [=our only chance of arriving on time is gone/lost]</vi> <vi>It's supposed to rain this weekend, so <it>there go</it> our plans for a barbecue. [=we won't be able to have a barbecue]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>to go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:still remaining <vi>There are only three more days <it>to go</it> until my birthday!</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>of food</ssl> <dt>:sold to be taken away and eaten somewhere else <vi>“I'd like a hamburger.” “For here or <it>to go</it>?” “<it>To go</it>.”</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="go[2]"> <hw hindex="2">go</hw> <altpr>ˈgoʊ</altpr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>goes</if></in> <def><sn>1</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <dt>:an attempt to do something <vi>“I can't get the window open.” “Let me <phrase>have a go</phrase> (at it).” [=let me try to do it]</vi> <vi>She's been thinking about learning to fly for many years, and she's finally decided to <phrase>give it a go</phrase>. [=she's finally decided to try doing it]</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) He managed to finish the work <phrase>in/at one go</phrase>. [=in one attempt, without stopping]</vi> <vi>(<it>chiefly Brit</it>) I don't know if this new medicine will help, but I think it's <phrase>worth a go</phrase>. [=it's worth a try]</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>singular</sgram> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:permission to do something <vi>My boss gave the project a <it>go</it>. [=my boss gave permission for the project to go ahead]</vi> <snote>In informal U.S. English, if you say that something <phrase>is a go</phrase>, you mean that it will or can happen in the way that was planned or hoped for. <vi>The rocket launch <it>is a go</it>.</vi> <vi>After many delays, we finally received word that the project <it>is a go</it>.</vi> If you say <phrase>all systems (are) go</phrase>, you mean that everything is working correctly so that something can continue or proceed in the planned or expected way. <vi>NASA officials have declared <it>all systems go</it> for the rocket launch.</vi> <vi>The problems have been fixed, and now <it>all systems are go</it>.</vi></snote></dt> <sn>3</sn> <sgram>noncount</sgram> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <ssl>informal</ssl> <dt>:energy that makes someone want to do many things <vi>a young reporter who's full of <it>go</it></vi> <dx>see also <dxt>get-up-and-go</dxt></dx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sgram>count</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:a turn in a game or other activity <vi>It's your <it>go</it>: they've had several <it>goes</it> already.</vi></dt></def> <dro><dre>all go</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:full of activity :very busy <vi>In this office it's <it>all go</it> all day without a break.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>have a go at</dre> <def><sl>Brit</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:to attack or criticize (someone) <vi>The press is <it>having a go at</it> the Prime Minister.</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>make a go of</dre> <def><dt>:to succeed in doing (something) <vi>He tried starting his own business, but he wasn't able to <it>make a go of</it> it. [=he wasn't able to succeed]</vi></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>no go</dre> <def><sl>US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt><un>used to say that something will not be allowed or cannot be done <vi>We tried and tried to get the computer running but it was just <it>no go</it>.</vi> <vi>I asked my boss for more time to finish the project, but she said <it>no go</it>. [=she said I could not have more time]</vi></un></dt></def></dro> <dro><dre>on the go</dre> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt>:very active or busy <vi>a housewife and mother who's always <it>on the go</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly Brit</ssl> <dt>:happening or going <vi>They have several projects <it>on the go</it> at the same time.</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="goes"> <hw>goes</hw> <dx>see <dxt>go</dxt></dx></entry>
	<entry id="went"> <hw>went</hw> <cx><cl>past tense of</cl> <ct>go</ct></cx></entry>
	<entry id="go-ahead[1]"> <hw hindex="1">go–ahead</hw> <sound><wav>goahea01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowəˌhɛd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <dro><dre>the go-ahead</dre> <def><dt>:permission to do something <vi>We've finally been <phrase>given the go-ahead</phrase> for the project.</vi> <vi>The company <phrase>received/got the go-ahead</phrase> to manufacture the new drug.</vi> <dx>see also <tag>go ahead</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dx></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="go-ahead[2]"> <hw hindex="2">go–ahead</hw> <altpr>ˈgowəˌhɛd</altpr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <ssl>US</ssl> <ssl>sports</ssl> <dt>:allowing a team to take the lead in a game <vi>He scored the <it>go-ahead</it> run/touchdown/goal.</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <sgram>more go–ahead; most go–ahead</sgram> <ssl>Brit</ssl> <dt>:having a lot of energy and desire to try new ideas and methods <vi>a vigorous <it>go-ahead</it> company</vi></dt></def> <dxnl>see also <tag>go ahead</tag> at <dxt>go</dxt></dxnl></entry>
	<entry id="go-around"> <hw>go–around</hw> <sound><wav>goarou01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgowəˌraʊnd</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>go–arounds</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>chiefly US</sl> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:<sx>go-round</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="go-between"> <hw>go–be*tween</hw> <sound><wav>gobetw01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊbəˌtwi:n</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>go–be*tweens</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <dt>:a person who talks to people or groups who disagree in order to help deal with or end the disagreement <vi>He'll act/serve as a <it>go-between</it> during the negotiations.</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="go-getter"> <hw>go–get*ter</hw> <sound><wav>gogett01.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊˈgɛtɚ</pr> <fl>noun</fl> <in><il>plural</il> <if>go–get*ters</if></in> <def><gram>count</gram> <sl>informal</sl> <dt>:a person who works very hard and who wants very much to succeed <vi>She's always been a real <it>go-getter</it>.</vi></dt></def> <uro><ure>go–get*ting</ure> <sound><wav>gogett02.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊˌgɛtɪŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <utxt><vi>a <it>go-getting</it> attitude</vi></utxt></uro></entry>
	<entry id="go-go"> <hw>go–go</hw> <sound><wav>gogo0001.wav</wav></sound> <pr>ˈgoʊˌgoʊ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl> <lb>always used before a noun</lb> <def><sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used to describe a woman who performs as a dancer to fast, energetic, popular music in a nightclub <vi><it>go-go</it> dancers</vi> <vi><it>go-go</it> girls</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly US</ssl> <dt>:relating to or involved in a time when many businesses are growing quickly and it is possible to make a lot of money <vi>He made a fortune during the market's <it>go-go</it> years.</vi> <vi>a <it>go-go</it> economy</vi></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>